人人影视
YYeTs.com
原创翻译  双语字幕
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多影视更新
请登陆www.YYeTs.com
你被监视着
You are being watched.
■
・ 翻译  面条打包子
・ 翻译  油炸电风扇
■
・ 翻译  茶炒栗子
政府有一套秘密系统
The government has a secret system--
■
・ 翻译  紫玉
・ 翻译  王小麦
一台每时每刻都在监控你的机器
a machine that spies on you every hour of every day.
■
・ 翻译  宅女之后
somehacker
幸田实果子
我设计这台机器是为了侦测恐怖行动
I designed the machine to detect acts of terror
■
・ 翻&校  阿好
但它却看到了一切
but it sees everything--
■
压制  灰灰是菇凉
牵涉普通人的暴力罪行
violent crimes involving ordinary people.
Kallen  Sage  Kallen  Sage  Kallen  Sage  Kallen  Sage  Kallen  Sage  Kallen  Sage  Kallen  Sage
■
时间轴
政府认为这些人无关紧要
The government considered these people irrelevant.
我们不
We don't.
受当局追捕  我们只能秘密活动
Hunted by the authorities, we work in secret.
你永远找不到我们
You'll never find us.
特效
灰灰
但无论是受害人还是行凶者
But victim or perpetrator,
总监
阿好
只要你的号码被列出来  我们就会找到你
if your number's up, we'll find you.
疑犯追踪
第三季 第三集
我来
I've got this.
不行
No, you don't.
你要暴露我们的身份了
You're gonna blow our cover.
我来划船
I'm rowing this boat.
有我在  别想
Not on my watch.
鉴于你们现在的身份
Given your cover,
让里瑟先生划
it might be more appropriate for Mr. Reese
比较适合  肖女士
to have the privilege, Ms. Shaw.
毕竟  你们是在装约会
You are supposed to be on a date, after all.
不用谢
You're welcome.
这罗密欧是谁啊
So who's our Romeo?
他叫伊恩・墨菲
His name is Ian Murphy.
他是名非常成功的投资人  投资项目包括
He's a successful investor in a variety of businesses--
咖啡馆  夜店  啤酒厂
a coffee house, a nightclub, a microbrewery.
他的资产情况如何
How's his portfolio?
也许是借了高利贷
Maybe he owes money to the wrong people.
没有  他的投资项目都很好
No, all his businesses are doing quite well,
信用报告很亮眼
and he has a stellar credit report.
他出身贫寒
He grew up quite destitute.
父母在他年少时就双双故去
His parents both died when he was just a teenager,
好心的叔父给他留了差不多十万美元
and then a kindly uncle left him nearly $100,000.
建议你们哪位
I suggest that one of you
赶在墨菲回家前去他休街南区的公寓查看一下
gets to Murphy's apartment in SOHO before he returns.
我们共度周末如何
What do you say we pick it up over the weekend?
我来做晚餐
I'll make you dinner.
我可是  厨艺高超
I happen to be a great chef.
既懂歌剧又会下厨的男人
A guy who knows his opera and can cook.
真叫我赞叹
I'm impressed.
那是同意了
Is that a yes?
是绝对同意
It's an absolutely.
我们得调头了  我得二十分钟内赶回上城区
We gotta head back. I gotta be Uptown in 20.
我这就去他公寓  芬奇
I'll go to his apartment, Finch.
查看一下
See what I can find.
好吧  但是该归我划了
Okay, but it's my turn to row this thing.
芬奇
Finch?
我似乎有发现了
I think I got something.
希望跟他的手机有关
I hope it's regarding his phone,
因为我失去他的信号了
because I've lost our connection.
我知道原因  那家伙瞬间从贵族范改颓废派了
I may know why. Our guy just went from blue blood to hipster
变身速度快得迅雷不及掩耳啊
faster than you can say "ironic facial hair".
我完全不明白你在说什么
I don't understand anything you just said.
他扔下约会对象  换了整套衣服  整身形象
He ditched his date, changed his clothes, his whole appearance.
他应该是有所图谋  我看肯定不是什么好事儿
So this guy's up to something and I'm betting it's nothing good.
刚到了墨菲的公寓
Just arrived at Murphy's apartment.
肖  墨菲那边有新情况吗
Shaw, you got an update on Murphy?
看来这小子是大众情人
It appears our boy's a ladies' man.
亿万富豪爱女当娜・威灵顿英年早逝
我跟着他到了威治一家小酒馆
I followed him to some dive in the Village.
新形象  新女伴
New image, new girl.
这家伙就像变色龙
Guy's a chameleon.
有条理  高效率  反社会
Organized, efficient, sociopathic.
倒也没什么不好
Not that there's anything wrong with that.
看来墨菲先生是从网上找约会对象的
It seems Mr. Murphy finds his dates online.
他认识女人多半是通过手机应用程序
He meets most of the women on smartphone applications
比如"干柴烈火"和"愿者上钩"
like Tinder and Angler.
会员注册档案后
Members put up a profile
就可以在指定地点签到
and then sign in at a given location.
太破坏恋爱的神秘感了
So much for keeping the mystery alive in a relationship.
芬奇  他留着记录
Finch, he's keeping records.
很详细  追踪过几十名女性
Detailed files, tracking dozens of women.
他怎么得到的信息
Where's he getting the information?
通过典型的跟踪网站
From your typical stalker sites.
愿者上钩
那种有严格背景审查的
Anything that promises a decent background check.
似乎他视她们为猎物
It's like he's hunting them.
我们何不直接把他拿下
Why don't we just take him out now?
就算他跟踪了
Just because he's a stalker
并不代表他就杀了人  肖女士
doesn't mean he's a killer, Ms. Shaw.
我倒不太确定  芬奇
I wouldn't be so sure, Finch.
他这里有张寻找失踪人员的传单
He's got a missing persons flyer
失踪的女子名叫詹娜・拉瑞兹
for a woman named Jenna Lakritz.
他还打印出了一篇文章
And there is an article he printed out...
内容是一名女子上周死亡
about a woman who died last week.
说是车祸
Says it was a car accident.
车祸是掩饰谋杀的好法子
Car accident's a good way to cover up a homicide.
所见略同
Exactly what I was thinking.
这家伙可能已经从跟踪升级到了谋杀
This guy may have graduated from stalker to killer after all.
介入必要性
目标身份[推论]
指派[3]
监控主体[已被篡改]
预测接近
执行人位置
主体位置
目标身份: 执行人
跟踪-活动中
指派[3]
目标身份: 146.1154.03A
跟踪-活动中
指派[2]
没有  夫人
No, Ma'am.
我们还在查医院
We're still searching hospitals,
不过就快找到她了
but we're closing in on her.
她在他眼皮底下工作了六个月
She worked on his desk for nearly six months.
知道组织的事
Knew about the program.
我认为梅女士很清楚
I have a feeling Ms. May knows exactly
北极光的位置
where Northern Lights is located.
就算不知道  至少我们能确定
If not, at least we'll know for sure.
然后我会搞定她
Then I'll take care of her.
也许扔到秘密据点关个几十年
Maybe a few decades in a black site.
或者不那么舒服的
Or something less cushy.
是  夫人
Yes, Ma'am.
我一查到地址马上电话给您
I'll call you as soon as I have a location.
你今天似乎冷静多了  罗宾
You seem calmer today, Robin.
是的
I am.
快到时间离开了
It's almost time for me to leave.
你要去哪里
Where is it that you're going?
这是个好问题
You know, that's a good question.
我还不确定
I'm not certain yet.
因为那声音会告诉你
Because the voice is going to tell you?
你慢慢懂了
You're catching on.
那声音现在正在对你说话吗
Is the voice speaking to you right now?
难道我像是在
Does it look like I'm talking
跟其他人说话吗  医生
to anyone other than you, Doctor?
你  你知道那手机
You--you realize that phone
并没有连接无线网络吧
Isn't connected to a wireless carrier.
上帝不需要美国电话电报公司
God doesn't need AT&T.
我不是已经向你证明了她的力量吗
Haven't I already proved to you just how powerful she is?
你确实证明了  你思维的力量
You've certainly proven the power of...your mind.
你已经展示了你非凡的智商
You've demonstrated great intelligence
和毋庸置疑的电脑技术
and no doubt computer skills.
你是借此才了解到了我那些见不得人的事
Which is how you learned all those nasty things about me.
你要知道  罗宾  人都会犯错
You know, Robin, we're all fallible.
不是所有人
Not all of us.
我想需要治疗的人是你
I suppose it's you who needs therapy.
看来你有很多要解决的问题
It sounds like you have a lot to work on.
我能帮你  罗宾
I can help you, Robin.
你现在陷入了地位幻想中
You suffer from delusions of grandeur,
这源自于你的内心深处的状况
something caused by your underlying condition.
这不是什么状况  这是未来
It's not a condition. It's the future.
等你明白到底发生什么事时
By the time you figure out what's really happening,
我已经超越了这现实
I'll have transcended this reality.
为什么你的"超越"
Why does your transcendence
要求你被关押在这里呢
require your imprisonment in this facility?
她自有计划
She has a plan.
什么计划
Which is what?
我还不知道
I don't know yet.
但我迫不及待了
But I can't wait to find out.
关于被墨菲跟踪的女人有发现没
Anything on the women Murphy's stalking?
失踪的詹娜・拉瑞兹
The missing woman, Jenna Lakritz,
是他的前女友
is a former girlfriend of his.
我可以查看她的手机历史
I'm able to look at her cell history,
但墨菲用了"短信无痕"
but Mr. Murphy uses VanishText,
这种程序可以使信息
an application designed to delete his messages
打开看过后马上被删除
as soon as they've been read.
颇有利于劈腿的  和杀人的
Good for cheaters... and killers.
那上周被杀的那姑娘呢
What about the girl that was killed last week?
当娜・威灵顿
Dana Wellington.
布鲁斯・威灵顿的女儿
Daughter of Bruce Wellington.
他是拍卖行老板  慈善家  地产大亨
Auction house owner, philanthropist, real estate magnate.
表面看来她和墨菲先生没什么联系
Can't seem to find anything connecting her to our Mr. Murphy,
但他们上的是同一所大学
except for the fact that they attended the same college.
里瑟先生  不是你
Mr. Reese, you didn't happen to purchase
给小熊买了新项圈吧
a new collar for Bear, did you?
还有他在咬的那个大得离谱的牛腿骨头
Or this gigantic cow femur that he's eating?
我最近忙着呢  芬奇
I've been a little busy, Finch.
看来也有人跟踪小熊了
Seems Bear has a stalker of his own.
说回墨菲先生
As for Mr. Murphy,
他经常去一家叫"残影"的夜店
he frequents a club called "Blur".
我交叉对比了你找到的文件中的女人
I ran the names from the files you discovered
和用"愿者上钩"软件的女人
against women who use the angler application.
他们都在那店夜店至少签到过一次
All of them have checked into that club at least once.
我今晚过去
I'll head there tonight.
我黑进那家夜店的数据库
I'll just access the club's database
帮你订个位子
and create a reservation for you.
且慢  我另有主意
Hold off on that. I may have another idea.
我们没有足够的证据叫警察
We don't have enough proof to call the cops.
但我们可以自己设个圈套
That doesn't mean we can't set up a trap of our own.
你有何建议
What are you suggesting?
既然不知道他有没有杀人
Till we can figure out if he's a killer or not,
那就暗中布个局
I say we stack the deck.
你好  警探
Hello, Detective.
你今晚能不能来趟安全屋
I was hoping you could come by the safe house tonight.
我想可以保证比
I think I can assure you it'll be more interesting than
逮捕大龄酒驾律师有意思多了
arresting aging corporate attorneys for driving under the influence.
能先给点提示吗
You wanna give me the headlines?
穿晚装来就行了
Only that it will require evening attire.
我的意思是  优雅的
What I mean to say is, something elegant,
但是  也不能太保守
but also... less than conservative.
这什么活儿啊  芬奇
Just what kind of job is this, Finch?
不赖嘛
Not bad.
毕竟上次见你还是躺在尸体袋里
Considering the last time I saw you, you were in a body bag.
更烂的地方我都待过
I've been in worse places.
我看应该行
I think this just might work.
原来好戏在这里啊
This is where the party is.
摩根女士
Ms. Morgan.
这是肖女士
This is Ms. Shaw,
卡特警探你已经见过了
and you know Detective Carter.
听说你起死回生了
Heard you came back from the dead.
只剩八条命了
Only eight more lives left.
意大利名鞋
扎诺蒂
Zanotti's?
好眼光
Good eye.
我们是诱饵
So we're your bait.
这么说不太好听
Rather a crude way of putting it,
不过也贴切
but I suppose it's apt.
目标就像变色龙  也许还杀过人
Our target is a chameleon and probable killer.
我真希望你们俩哪次叫我来
Just once, I wish you fellas would call
是可以不用带家伙的
with something that didn't require a firearm.
为什么  你没带吗
Why? Are you not carrying?
我才不会打无准备之仗
I know better than to show up unprepared.
意大利名枪
这是贝雷塔迷你吗
You have the Nano?
我超想要一把
I've been dying for one of these.
欢迎随时借用
You can borrow it any time.
真美
It's pretty.
约翰送的小礼物
Little gift from John.
那么
And...
大家都武装到位了
now that everyone is sufficiently well-armed,
我已经替你们在"愿者上钩"建好了档案
I've taken the liberty of creating profiles for all of you on Angler.
所以请尽快下载程序
So please, download this application onto your phones
以便今天晚上一到夜店就签到
so that you can check in once you arrive at the club.
我要看我的档案
I'd like to see that profile.
娜德雅・费拉罗
瑜伽教练
纽约休街南区
任我整控者  来者不拒
真的吗
Really?
瑜伽教练
A yoga instructor?
你想换成职业杀手
You'd prefer trained killer?
墨菲先生喜欢用这个程序寻找目标
Mr. Murphy favors this application when looking for new targets.
至于吸引他的注意力
And as far as getting his attention,
我想没多大问题
I doubt that will be an issue.
你要用魅力  肖
You'll have to use your charm, Shaw...
别用暴力
not your sidearm.
希望你没问题
I hope that's not a problem.
这话什么意思
What is that supposed to mean?
我长得不好看吗
I don't look good?
我长得挺好看啊
'Cause I think I look good.
你长得还行  肖
You look fine, Shaw.
就是  成天凶巴巴的
You just look...angry all the time.
我们教她  上车再说
We'll work on it in the car.
? Tonight ?
? Give me everything tonight ?
目标在哪儿
So where's our target?
经理说午夜才出现
Manager says he shows around midnight.
那来这么早干什么
Then what are we doing here so early?
两个小子拿咱们当杀手的诱饵
I was not gonna let those boys send us off as killer bait
我可不能便宜了他们
without getting something in return.
我喜欢你的范儿
I like your style.
抱歉  姑娘们  我只喝烈的
Sorry, girls, my system only runs on diesel.
第一杯敬什么呢
So what should we drink to?
希望都别被连环杀手宰了
Here's hoping nobody gets serial killed.
好了姑娘们  签到吧
Okay, ladies, time for us to check in.
? More than I should tonight ?
? And I'm gonna take you home with me ?
? If I could tonight ?
楼上如何  弗斯科
How you doing up there, Fusco?
没问题
Yeah, all clear.
但这儿太坑爹了
Although this place is a rip-off.
汽水都要5刀
Club soda cost me $5.
不过"景色"不错
Nice view though.
乔丝
Joss.
放松
Relax.
莱奈尔在楼上  约翰在外边
Lionel's upstairs, John's outside.
肖随时准备给偷瞄她的人来一枪
Shaw's ready to shoot anybody who looks at her sideways.
去玩玩吧
Let's go have fun.
附议
I second that.
好吧
Okay.
? So don't even try ?
? Everywhere we are, you're there ?
? I know you've lost your mind ?
? I know you know ?
? I know you know he's mine ?
? It's plain to see that he's with me ?
你好啊
How you doing?
注意了  姑娘们
Heads up, ladies.
那小子到了
Our boy just landed.
? Got a problem with limitations ?
? Can't restrain your dedications ?
? To turn back time ?
乔丝林・卡特
警员
纽约曼哈顿
别担心  我把佩枪留在家里了
? Ruin mine ?
? Start again ?
? But that's not fine ?
? Now you call him like you're crazy ?
? Like you're crazy, you must be crazy ?
? Drunken moments forget he dates me ?
? But you just saw us at the club ?
? And now you hate me ?
? I know you know he's mine ?
能坐你旁边吗
Do you mind if I join you?
当然
Sure.
? I know you know, I know you know ?
我很敬佩你的职业  乔丝
So I got a lot of respect for what you do, Joss.
外面的世界很恐怖
It's a scary world out there.
正是
Very true.
都不知道会遇到什么变态
You never know what kinda creeps you'll run into.
我都不敢相信警察可以这么辣
I can't believe that they allow cops to be so sexy though.
这应该都违法了
There should be a law against that.
好吧
All right.
我不该说这种花言巧语
I should know better than to give you a line.
不过我喜欢你的笑容
I do like the way you smile though.
又是花言巧语
Another line.
不  是真心的
No, not even a little bit.
我明晚为你烹饪晚餐吧
Let me make you dinner tomorrow night.
好让我再练练嘴皮子
I'll work on my witty banter.
我厨艺很棒
I happen to be a great cook.
这是我的众多才能之一
It's one of my many talents.
这是我们的机会  卡特警探
This is our chance, Detective Carter.
拜托同意
Please say yes.
同意
Yes.
注意  搭档
Heads up, partner.
目标在看着你
Our guy's watching you.
他在跟踪你
Now he's tailing you.
还在跟着你
He's still on your tail,
所以别回家  明白吗
So don't go home, okay?
那我该去哪  弗斯科
Where am I supposed to go, Fusco?
你还好吧
Are you okay?
我没事
Yeah, I'm good.
他去哪儿了
Where'd he go?
我看着他在那条街上走了
I saw the guy disappear up the street.
要是他在找下一个目标
Safe to say if he was looking for his next victim,
看来是找到了
he found her.
里瑟先生在哪儿
Where's Mr. Reese?
陪卡特等着她今晚的约会
Staying out with Carter till her date tonight.
乖宝贝
Good boy.
他九年前收到的那笔钱  我追踪到来源了
I have had some luck tracing the money he received nine years ago.
我还以为是他叔叔给的
I thought it came from his uncle.
其实是来自一家瑞士的空壳公司
Actually, it came from a shell corporation out of Switzerland,
注资人是布鲁斯・威灵顿
funded by Bruce Wellington.
看来还是和死去的女孩有关系
So there's a connection to the dead girl after all.
看
Look.
这是墨菲其中一个手机卡的GPS地图
This is a GPS map of one of Murphy's SIM cards.
他上周去过汉普顿
He was in the Hamptons last week.
正是当娜・威灵顿葬礼那天
Same day as Dana Wellington's funeral.
这变态可能是去回味他的犯罪了
Sicko was probably reliving his crime.
也许卡特约会时能发现更多信息
Maybe Carter can get more info on her date.
我们要吃什么
So what are we having?
别担心  肯定不含坚果
Don't worry. Nothing with tree nuts.
你怎么知道我会过敏
How did you know I was allergic?
我有心啊  男人要是肯这么做
I pay attention. See, if more guys did that,
就会发现异性没那么难懂
they'd find the opposite sex less confusing.
这不是答案
That's not an answer.
你在酒吧时推开了一小碟杏仁
You pushed away a little bowl of almonds at the club.
你的表情像是在自我保护
Your face said it was out of protection,
所以  严重的坚果过敏
so, severe nut allergy, hmm?
你是当警探的好材料
You'd make a good detective.
有意思
You know, that's funny.
我也这么想你呢
I was thinking the same thing about you.
什么意思
What do you mean?
你在酒吧里看其他人的方式
The way you were watching everyone in the club.
我知道你在"愿者上钩"的档案说你是警员
I know your Angler profile says you're an officer,
但  我感觉你更像警探
but...you seem more like a detective to me.
我以前是警探
I was a detective.
凶案组的
Homicide.
但现在不是了
But I'm doing something different now.
我没想到会这样
It's not where I thought I would wind up,
不过现在就这样了
but it's where I need to be right now.
他在干什么  要我开枪吗
What's he doing? Should I shoot him?
-先不要  -什么
- Not yet. - What?
抱歉
Sorry.
只是香菇而已
Just shiitake mushrooms.
我不是要抱你  时机未到
I wasn't making a move, yet.
她刚才全无防备
She doesn't have her guard up.
你开玩笑呢
You're joking.
那女人防得滴水不漏
That woman's got a guard of steel.
你们俩有点什么事吗
You two have thing or something?
我一眼就看出你和佐伊有事
'Cause, I mean, I clocked you and Zoe right off the bat,
但我没想到你和卡特
but I never thought you and Carter--
我们只是朋友
We're just friends.
你的"朋友"做得很好
Your "just friend" is doing her job.
她博取了那人的信任
She gets this guy to trust her,
他也许就会行动
maybe he makes a move.
那就可以开枪了
And we can finally shoot him.
那你做什么工作呢  伊恩
So what do you do for a living, Ian?
我是几家小公司的股东
I own pieces of a bunch of small companies.
怎么起步的
How did you get started?
亲友帮忙吗
Help from friends or family?
差不多
Kinda.
我17岁起就开始自己生活
I've been an emancipated minor since I was 17.
有一天我在学校时  几个律师出现
One day I'm in college, some lawyer shows up
给了我张十万的支票
with a check for 100 grand.
来自我一位从没见过面的叔叔
From some uncle I've never met,
然后突然间  我  就有了选择
and all of a sudden I had these options.
以前从没有过
Never really had those before.
于是就开始做生意
So I started my own business.
如果我注定孤独
If I was gonna be alone,
至少要孤独得舒服一点
I was gonna do it on my own terms.
那么
So...
你和佐伊当了多久的  特殊朋友
how long have you and Zoe been...special friends?
我没数过日子  肖
I haven't really counted the days, Shaw.
你呢
What about you?
最近约会没
Any big dates lately?
忙着从坏人手里拯救世界呢
Been too busy saving the world from bad guys.
而且  恋爱要折腾
Besides, relationships are for amateurs.
如今的男人都太  情绪化
Guys these days have so many...emotions.
哭哭啼啼  要哄要抱
They cry, they wanna be held.
我不知道要拿他们怎么办
I just don't know what to do with them.
你是要当尼姑吗
So you--you're a nun?
我是实用主义者  约翰
I'm a pragmatist, John.
我会出门  享受一晚  或者三晚
I go out, have a fun night, or three.
然后  忘掉
And then, uh, I move on, you know?
无烦无恼
No muss, no fuss.
密码  谢谢
Password, please.
我的手有点抖
My hands are a little shaky.
应该是[抗精神病药]氯丙嗪的副作用吧
Side effect from the thorazine, I suppose.
你帮我输一下好吗
Would you mind typing it in for me?
谢谢
Thank you.
罗纳尔多・卡尔迈克医生处方
Prescription from Dr. Ronald Carmichael.
[麻醉药]地氟醚
Desflurane.
两瓶  谢谢
Two vials, please.
不  要三瓶
No, make it three.
你不用送我的
You didn't have to walk me out.
我可不想让你一个人等车
I didn't want you waiting for a cab all by yourself.
我知道  你是警察  但是
I know, you're a cop, but--
但是你是绅士
But you're a gentleman.
我尽量
I try.
今晚跟你很开心  乔丝
I had a really nice time with you tonight, Joss.
我也是
Yeah, I did too.
而且  你说得对
And you know what, you were right.
那确实是最美味的智利海鲈
That was the best Chilean sea bass I've ever had.
那就好
Good.
两个混混朝你走过去了  卡特
Two bogies coming your way, Carter.
好好  伙计
All right. All right, guys.
别动粗  伙计
No need for violence, guys.
想要什么尽管拿去
Just, you know, take what you want.
你很不走运  伊恩
Unfortunately for you, Ian,
我们要的不是你的钱包
we're not here for your wallet.
准备好了么
Ready?
好了  好了
Ready, ready.
射得漂亮  肖
Nice aim, Shaw.
彼此彼此
Back at you.
伊恩  你还好吗
Ian, are you okay?
我肯定会好
I'd be a hell of a lot better
但你得先说说你到底是谁  乔丝
if you told me who you actually were, Joss.
新密码
确认
我从那俩阿呆和阿瓜那儿弄到了点有趣的消息
I got some interesting information from muggers Dumb and Dumber.
我猜他们是受雇于他人
I imagine they were hired hands?
正中
Bingo.
说是一个叫基普・戴维斯的人雇了他们
Said a guy by the name of Kip Davis hired them.
我查了查
I made a few calls,
发现这个戴维斯
found out this guy, Davis,
是布鲁斯・威灵顿的安全主管
head of security for Bruce Wellington.
这肯定不是巧合
And that's certainly not a coincidence.
谢谢你  警探
Thank you, Detective.
我懂了  但是你们怎么知道
I get that, but how did you know
有人要害我
that someone was gonna come after me?
我们有内部消息说有人要杀了你
We had inside information that someone wanted you dead.
或者是反过来
or maybe it was the other way around.
等等
Wait.
你  你认为我会害人
W--you th--you think I'd hurt someone?
我们看过你藏的跟踪资料了  伊恩
We've seen your stalker stash, Ian.
我不是在跟踪
It's not stalking.
我是在研究
It's research.
女人们喜欢我猜到她们的需求
Women like that I can anticipate their needs.
她们习惯了男人什么都不做
They're used to guys doing the bare minimum.
我就尽量多做
I go above and beyond.
试试吧
Try it sometime.
你视她们为猎物
You're hunting them.
我想要她们的信息  她们直接给我了
I want their info, they're giving it to me straight up.
是  我的调查有点太过"尽职"了
And, yeah, I get a little overly efficient in my due diligence,
但是
But...
她们喜欢
they like it.
如果她们那么喜欢
If they liked it so much,
为什么那些感情都不持久
how come those relationships don't last?
本来就该那样
They're not supposed to.
那才是关键
It's kind of the point.
墨菲先生  为什么布鲁斯・威灵顿要杀了你
Mr. Murphy, why would Bruce Wellington want you dead?
你是不是曾跟他女儿有染
Were you involved with his daughter?
伊恩  告诉我们实情
Ian. Tell us what's going on
我们才能帮你
so we can help you.
当娜跟我
Dana and I...
我们认识时  她还在大学读书
we met when she was still in college
而我在酒吧拼命工作挣钱  偿还学费贷款
and I was tending bar, trying to keep up with my student loans,
我们相爱了
and we fell in love.
不需要任何研究
No research needed.
那位财富五百强的老爸不希望他女儿
Mr. Fortune 500 did not appreciate his daughter
和穷南方佬约会
dating poor white southie trash,
但是  当娜怀孕了
but...then Dana got pregnant.
你们要知道
Now you gotta understand this.
威灵顿  他用铁腕手段治家  所以
Wellington, he rules that family with an iron fist. So...
一天  威灵顿的手下找到我家
one day one of Wellington's lackeys shows up at my door
跟我说  当娜堕胎了
and he tells me that, Dana got an abortion,
然后  给了我一张支票
and, he gives me a check,
他说  我得离开这城市
and he says that I have to get out of town
否则威灵顿会毁掉我
or Wellington will ruin me.
你就收下了钱
So you took the money?
当娜是我的全部
Dana was all I had in the world.
我给她打了一百多次电话  而她
And I must have called her a hundred times, and she...
从没回复我
never called me back.
她太害怕她父亲
She was terrified of her father.
所有人都害怕
They all were.
那是九年前的事情了
And that was nine years ago.
从那以后  我和她和她的家人就断了联系
And I haven't had anything to do with her or her family since.
直到你去参加她的葬礼
Until you went to her funeral.
我怎能不去呢
How could I not go?
威灵顿看见了我
Wellington saw me
大发雷霆  大喊大叫
and he flipped out and started screaming,
就在当娜的墓旁
right there at Dana's grave.
都这么久了  他为什么还那么恨你
Why would he be so upset with you after all this time?
我不知道  乔丝
I don't know, Joss.
我发誓
I swear.
我也没留下查问
I didn't stay to find out.
我喜欢小熊的新项圈
I like Bear's new collar.
这才合他的风格
Seemed more his style.
那根恐龙骨头也是你买的吗
That dinosaur bone from you as well?
对啊  看他多喜欢
Yeah, he loves that thing.
他的消化系统颇持异议
His intestines beg to differ.
肖
Shaw.
看看这个
Take a look at this.
你们和我想得一样吗
Are you both seeing what I'm seeing?
孩子多大  八岁  九岁
That kid's what? Eight? Nine?
看来我们知道威灵顿先生为什么要杀伊恩了
I suppose we now know why Mr. Wellington wants Ian dead.
当娜根本没堕胎
Dana didn't have an abortion after all.
爸爸可能觉得伊恩出席葬礼
Daddy probably figured Ian showed up at the funeral
会带走他的继承人
to take away his heir.
我想我们该见见威灵顿先生了
I think it's time we meet Mr. Wellington in person.
卡特警探要怎么告诉伊恩呢
What should Detective Carter tell Ian?
实情
The truth.
我不明白
I don't understand.
当娜的姐姐  玛丽莎  把他当成自己的孩子
Dana's sister, Marissa, raised him as her own.
她比当娜大十岁
She was ten years older.
我想当时她
I imagine she seemed
更合适当家长
like a more suitable parent at the time.
他们怎么能这样对我
How could they do this to me?
当娜为什么撒谎
Why would Dana lie?
如你所说
Like you said,
威灵顿先生有权有势
Mr. Wellington is a very powerful man,
为保全颜面不择手段
willing to do anything to keep up appearances.
当娜知道只有说谎
Dana knew that a lie
才能让你离开波士顿
was the only thing that would get you to leave Boston.
那他就夺走了我的一切
So he gets to take everything from me.
我的家  我的孩子
My--my home and my--my child?
不  伊恩  不会
No, Ian. He doesn't.
因为我们会纠正这一切
Because we're going to set things right.
怎么做
How?
芬奇会打开孩子的储物柜
Finch is going to break into the kid's locker,
拿走艾利克斯的学生水瓶
take Alex's school-issued water bottle,
拿去做DNA测试
and use it for the DNA test.
这个计划看上去挺妥
Sounds like a safe enough plan.
我和他一起去
I'm going with him.
这不妥  伊恩
It's not safe, Ian.
我只想看一眼我的孩子  乔丝
All I wanna do is put eyes on my son, Joss.
也许我再没机会了
In case I don't get the chance again.
先生
Sir?
摩根女士
Ms. Morgan.
谢谢你抽空见我们  威灵顿先生
Thank you for meeting with us, Mr. Wellington.
咱们的老朋友最近怎么样
And how's our mutual friend?
她让我向你问好
She sends her best.
这是约翰・威利  她提过的那位收藏家
This is John Wiley, the collector she told you about.
佐伊说你能找到别人找不到的珍品
Zoe says you're a man who can find things no one else can.
她太抬举我了  不过的确如此
She flatters me, but it's also true.
我在寻找一幅私人收藏的毕加索作品
I'm looking for a privately owned Picasso.
《手捧白鸽的儿童》
Child With a Dove.
钱不是问题
I'm willing to pay whatever it takes.
恕我失陪了  我要去补个妆
If you boys will excuse me, I need to powder my nose.
漂亮
Nice entrance.
谢了  保险箱在哪儿
Thanks. Where's the safe?
老派啊
Old school.
棒极了
Excellent.
就算证明了孩子是伊恩的
You know, proving the kid is Ian's
也摆脱不掉威灵顿
may not get Wellington off his back.
我只管开保险箱
I'm just the safecracker.
那种麻烦事就留给哈罗德吧
I leave the messy stuff to Harold.
你最好动作快点  肖
You better hurry up, Shaw.
看起来威灵顿打算带他外孙
Looks like Wellington is about to take his grandson
去国外待一段时间了
on a long trip outside the country.
他们要带他去哪儿
Where are they taking him?
艾利克斯要去伦敦的一所寄宿学校读书
Alex has been enrolled at a London boarding school.
他们明天早上走
They leave tomorrow morning.
所以就这样了
So it's over.
即使我们拿到了DNA样本
Even if we get a DNA sample,
也不能阻止威灵顿对我下杀手
that won't stop Wellington from trying to kill me.
只要我们善用亲子鉴定就能
It will if we leverage the child's paternity.
威灵顿只关心他的家族传承
The Wellington legacy is all he cares about.
我敢保证  像他这种人
I can assure you, a man like this
会不择手段地保护他的名誉
will do anything to protect his name.
我失陪一下
Excuse me for a moment.
黑色  千克  探戈
Black. Kilo. Tango.
企鹅  阿尔法  千克
Penguin. Alpha. Kilo.
亚历克斯
怀亚特
斯通牧场医院
Stone Ranch hospital.
你好  我想询问下罗宾・法罗女士的近况
Yes, hello. I was calling to check up on Ms. Robin Farrow.
我是她叔叔  哈罗德・冉
This's her uncle, Harold Wren.
你好  冉先生
Hello, Mr. Wren.
罗宾情况不错
Robin is doing quite well.
您是今天第二个打电话问候她的人了
Although you're the second person to call on her today.
第一个人是谁
Who was the first?
他不肯告诉我们姓名
He wouldn't give us a name,
所以我们没有告诉他任何信息
so we wouldn't give him any information.
约瑟夫呢
Where's Joseph?
他  今天请病假了
He called in sick today.
我是伊恩
I'm Ian.
系好安全带吧
So, buckle up.
已经系好了
I already did.
里瑟先生
Mr. Reese.
我想墨菲先生刚才绑架了他儿子
I believe Mr. Murphy just kidnapped his son.
他的出生证明不在这里
His birth certificate isn't here.
DNA测试要花好几天
It takes days to run DNA.
威灵顿一家明天就要出国了
The Wellingtons leave the country tomorrow.
里瑟
Reese.
你说得对
You're right,
绝对是后现代主义杰作
that is a lovely depiction of postmodernism.
不过  能问你件事吗
But, may I ask you something?
什么事  威利先生
What's that, Mr. Wiley?
你外孙的出生证明放在哪儿了
Where is your grandson's birth certificate?
你把孩子从他父亲身边偷走
You stole a child from his father.
艾利克斯有父亲
Alex has a father.
不
No.
艾利克斯只有姨妈和姨父
Alex has an aunt and an uncle
充当他的父母
who raised him as their own.
我再问你一遍  威灵顿先生
I'm going to ask you one more time, Mr. Wellington.
你外孙的出生证明放在哪儿了
Where is your grandson's birth certificate?
我外孙永远都不会知道
My grandson will never know
那个白种穷鬼是他父亲
that piece of white trash is his father.
艾利克斯是继承人  不是佣人
Alex is an heir, not the help.
保安会送你们出去
Security will show you out.
你再不动手  我就上了
If you weren't gonna do that, I was.
好吧
Okay.
现在做什么
What do we do now?
伊恩  你在哪里
Ian, where are you?
我刚干了件愚蠢至极的事
I just did something really stupid.
我一般一放学就回家了
I usually go home right after school.
是啊  我想我们今天可以来点不一样的
Yeah, I thought we could do something different today.
为什么  今天是什么日子
Why? What's today?
艾利克斯
Alex,
我很早以前就认识你妈妈了
I-I knew your mom a long time ago.
如果我回家晚了她会生气的
She gets mad if I come home late.
是啊
Right.
我想她不会的
I'm sure she doesn't.
我是想说  我认识你的当娜姨妈
What I meant to say was I knew your aunt Dana.
当娜姨妈去世了
Aunt Dana died.
是啊  我知道
Yeah, I know.
我还知道你很难过
And I know that makes you really sad.
我也很难过
Makes me sad too.
至爱从你的生命中消失
To have someone you love just vanish from your life.
确实很难接受  即便你长大后也一样
It's hard to understand, even when you're grown up.
你是怎么认识她的
How did you know her?
在学校吗
From school?
是啊
Yeah.
看
See?
我们是好朋友
We were good friends.
我小时候她总是读故事书给我听
She used to read me stories when I was little.
等我长大点儿了  她就让我读给她听
Then I got older and--and she let me read to her.
她喜欢《哈利・波特》
She liked Harry Potter.
真希望我没跟她失去联系
I wish I hadn't lost touch with her.
真希望
I wish I had...
我能早点认识你
met you a lot sooner.
为什么
Why?
感觉就很想认识你
You seem like someone I'd really like to know.
艾利克斯
Alex.
我是卡特警员  来接你回家
I'm Officer Carter, here to take you home.
但首先我得先跟我的朋友伊恩谈一下
But first I need to talk to my friend Ian for a minute.
不如这样
Tell you what.
你去给自己买个冰淇淋  好吗
Why don't you go buy yourself an ice cream, okay?
好的
Okay.
我一动手就意识到那样很蠢
I knew it was a stupid move the second I did it,
但是  我刚刚知道自己有个儿子
but that's -- I just found out that I have a son.
现在这些人  还想要
Now these people, they wanna
再次把他从我身边夺走
just take him away from me again?
我不会允许的  伊恩
I'm not gonna let that happen, Ian,
但我们得光明正大地来
But we gotta do this right.
我还没告诉你  我多喜欢你穿警服的样子
I never told you how much I liked the uniform.
又是花言巧语
Another line?
是真心的
Not even a little.
我朋友的朋友的朋友
Friend of mine knows people who know people
出生证明
母亲
当娜・E・威灵顿
父亲
伊恩・D・墨菲
母亲  当娜・E・威灵顿
父亲  伊恩・D・墨菲
掌握了富豪名人御用医生的把柄
that have dirt on doctors to the rich and famous.
我正准备要作为证物提交
I'm about to submit that into evidence.
那么  你准备好真正做父亲了吗
So, are you ready to be a father for real?
绝对超出你想象
More than you could possibly know.
我为你高兴
I'm happy for you.
也为艾利克斯
And for Alex.
要出去喝一杯庆祝吗
Happy enough to celebrate over a drink?
等一切尘埃落定吧
Maybe after the dust settles.
你有我的号码
You still have my number.
是啊
Yeah.
你今晚有什么不一样吗  罗宾
What's different about you tonight, Robin?
我感觉安心了
I feel relieved,
如释重负
like a great weight's been lifted.
听你这么说我很高兴
I'm so pleased to hear that.
看来你吃的药有效果了
It sounds like your medication is working.
不
No.
是我终于可以离开了
It's finally time for me to leave.
这样啊
I see.
罗宾  你离开这里的唯一方法
Okay, Robin, the only way you can leave this facility
是我签字批准
is with my signature,
但近期不可能
which you're not gonna get any time soon.
你得积极配合治疗
You need to start participating in your therapy.
这样才能好转
It's the only way to get well.
我在配合啊
I am participating.
可以说  很受启发
And it's been...educational, to say the least,
但有名政府特工
but there's a government operative
要来杀我
who's coming to kill me,
也就是说  你我时间不多了
which means you and I have run out of time.
好吧  这听起来
Okay, that sounds to me like
就像是所谓的受迫害情结
what we call a persecution complex.
他可非常真实  我敢保证
He's quite real, I assure you.
所以  很可惜
So, you see, sadly,
我得走了
I need to be moving on.
好吧
Okay.
那  你要逃跑
So, you're going to escape?
你打算怎么做
And how do you plan on doing that?
首先  你桌子上的电话会响
First the phone on your desk will ring.
她要告诉我时间到了
She'll be letting me know it's time.
然后我会猛击你的颈动脉
Then I'll punch you in the carotid artery.
会很疼  罗纳尔多  但你死不了
It'll hurt, Ronald, but it won't kill you.
然后我会拿走你的车钥匙
Then I'll take your car keys.
那警卫呢  你打算怎么处理他们
And the guards, how--how will you manage them?
我不用处理
I won't have to.
他们会因为吸入通风系统里的地氟醚
They'll be incapacitated from the desflurane
而暂时瘫痪
in the ventilation system.
地氟醚会在华氏75度时汽化
It vaporizes at 75 degrees.
大楼的温度控制中心
Which the building climate control
已经设定好十分钟前到达这一温度
has been programmed to reach ten minutes ago.
好吧  你听到的那个声音
Okay, this voice that you hear,
她会  她会做所有这些事
she is--she's gonna do all this?
当然不
Of course not.
她看到了一切
She sees everything,
但是她自己能做的却不多
but there's very little she can do about it herself.
所以才需要我
That's where I come in.
她告诉我该做什么  然后我去做
She tells me what to do and I do it.
她确实帮我从自动配药机里
She did help me a little with stealing the desflurane
偷出了地氟醚
from the automatic dispensing system.
别担心
Don't worry.
我两天前就关了你办公室的通风口
I closed the vents in your office two days ago.
现在外面应该搞定了
It should have cleared out by now.
你听到外面多安静了吗
Do you hear how quiet it is out there?
一定是时间要到了
Must be almost time.
你跟我一样激动吗
Are you as excited about this as I am?
未知号码来电
你还要让他等多久
How long are you gonna keep him waiting?
他答应要送我回家了
He promised to walk me home.
真有骑士精神
Very chivalrous of him.
好吧
Okay, fine.
我该走了
I should probably get going.
是啊  我也要走了
Yeah, I need to go too.
我还有约
I have a date.
跟我儿子
With my son.
今晚干得漂亮  姑娘们
Nice work tonight, ladies.
晚安
Good night.
你觉得呢
What do you think?
想走吗
You wanna get out of here?
好吧
Okay.
但你得去我那儿睡
But you're sleeping at my place.
你好啊
Hello there.
上帝啊
Oh, my God.
你干了什么
What have you done?
别担心  我没杀他们
Don't worry. I didn't kill them.
就像你说的  我有进步了
Like you said, I've been making progress.
但是要来杀我的那个人
The man coming after me, on the other hand,
却一定会杀了你  所以
will almost certainly kill you, so...
你大概应该逃命了
You probably should run.
借过
Pardon me.
你真以为她会抛弃我吗
Did you really think she would abandon me?
真的吗  这家伙都不行
Really? Even this guy?
反正你是老大
I guess you're the boss.
再见了  医生
So long, Doc.
谢谢你的帮助
And thanks for all the help.
我真的觉得好多了
I think I really am much better now.
芬奇  出什么事了
Finch, what's wrong?
里瑟先生  我们有麻烦了
Mr. Reese, we have a problem.